<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Raul Herrador</title><description>Thoughts, stories and ideas of a Software Engineer student</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><generator>Ghost 0.11</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 20:21:29 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>Do not surround yourself with toxic people</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Everybody will have to deal with toxic people in a way or another, at university, at work maybe even with some relative. What this post is about is how i use to deal with these kind of people driven by envy, or just by their own boredom. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id="howcanyourecognizeatoxicperson"&gt;How can you&lt;/h5&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/do-not-surround-yourself-with-toxic-people/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">350eab59-1057-4ad6-8d95-99d6633e0cbb</guid><category>personal</category><category>toxic-people</category><category>good-vibes-only</category><category>reflections</category><dc:creator>Raul HC</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 19:54:46 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/11/logo-good-vibes.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/11/logo-good-vibes.png" alt="Do not surround yourself with toxic people"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everybody will have to deal with toxic people in a way or another, at university, at work maybe even with some relative. What this post is about is how i use to deal with these kind of people driven by envy, or just by their own boredom. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id="howcanyourecognizeatoxicperson"&gt;How can you recognize a toxic person?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every person I've met with this sort of behavior usually are easy to recognize by their lack of motivation in life. These are some of the behaviors that characterize them in my humble opinion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For them only exists their way of doing something and that’s the correct way. &lt;strong&gt;This is obviously not true&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They will throw at you phrases that can be summarize to 'you can't do X thing' or '...but you don't know anything about X'. &lt;strong&gt;This a form of underestimating you and your skills&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Usually they have a strong tendency to make judgments about other people with absolutely zero or very little knowledge about them.  &lt;strong&gt;You don’t know what someone has been through, you don’t know his story so you don’t judge another person&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They will try to stop you from doing what you want and they won't stop trying to drag you to the things they're good at and they can maintain a dominant position over you. &lt;strong&gt;This way they will always be &lt;em&gt;above you&lt;/em&gt; and will keep you from improve&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another way to recognize a toxic person is looking at what he talks about a thing. If he only talks about the negative aspects and emphasize them instead of centering the conversation in the good parts, well …, begin to suspect. &lt;strong&gt;They are negative people by nature and instead of lifting you they will try to push you down&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id="whattodo"&gt;What to do&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My personal experience says that the best option is to try to avoid them under all circumstances. But as I told you at the beginning of this post you will deal with people of all kinds during life so don’t worry, it’s just another experience you have to go through. In consequence, if you are forced to work in any way with people of this kind, just try to keep a cordial and professional relationship with them, do not include them in your social circles nor your life.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as a final advice, one I use myself, transform their attempts of making you desist in an extra boost of energy to get to your goals. As one quote I read once, &lt;em&gt;Tell me I can’t, then watch me work twice as hard to prove you wrong&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a nice day :)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Thoughts on my internship interview</title><description>&lt;p&gt;This is my final year at university as Software Engineer Student and we need to complete at least 120 hours working in a company as a part of one of the &lt;em&gt;'subjects'&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process starts with a list of offering companies and every student enrolled in the course choose several&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/thoughts-on-my-internship-interview/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">925a6b2a-b963-42e6-8c72-c3f928d2c1c1</guid><category>interview</category><category>internship</category><category>experience</category><dc:creator>Raul HC</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 11:23:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/11/job-interviewpng.png" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/11/job-interviewpng.png" alt="Thoughts on my internship interview"&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is my final year at university as Software Engineer Student and we need to complete at least 120 hours working in a company as a part of one of the &lt;em&gt;'subjects'&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process starts with a list of offering companies and every student enrolled in the course choose several options in order of preference. Then the course staff start to sort by average grade mainly the students. The output of this process is a list of students who should contact the respective companies to start the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, so my first company choice was &lt;a href="http://csc.com"&gt;CSC&lt;/a&gt;, a very large company  located in Avilés (also Barcelona, Madrid, etc). I contacted the human resources person who was responsible of the agreement with my &lt;a href="http://www.uniovi.es/en/inicio"&gt;university&lt;/a&gt; and sent her the english version of my resumé. After a couple of weeks I received a call asking me to go to their offices in Avilés next day. I accepted to be there at mid-morning to realize the internship interview. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id="theinterview"&gt;The interview&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I arrived at their offices a little bit early because I try to follow the rule &lt;em&gt;'5 Minutes early is on time; on time is late; late is unacceptable.'&lt;/em&gt; I had to sign a sort of contract to enter the building and keep in view the visitor's accreditation that I was given. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few minutes two men, one from Spain and one foreigner, came and introduce themselves. They were part of the IT systems department of the company. All of us went to a meeting room where they started asking me some questions about my CV (they'd printed it and underline the parts they were more interested in). When we finished talking two of the DevOps engineers of the company and one of the development department entered the room and introduced themselves. They asked me kind of the same things that the other team and some questions about their respective job tasks, like if I was familiar with some of the concepts. We also talked about some of the technologies the company use in daily task and a little about how things work there. I explained them why I think university is a little obsolete and the disconnection that exists between the institution and the real-world companies. We also talked about some of my hobbies, what project I was working on for my final course between others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wouldn't like to finish without adding I felt really comfortable talking with all of these people, specially because they were actual workers of the company and I had the opportunity to ask them some technical questions related to the task I would be doing. In fact it was more like a relaxed conversation between engineers who like working on what they do. All of this process was realized in Spanish and English to test my conversational skills . I didn't wanted to fool anybody about my english level and I liked the idea to talk a little in the Shakespeare's language even though I'm not the best english speaker xD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;UPDATE: Today I received a call from CSC's human resources department telling me I was one of the selected candidates. Hooray!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Welcome!</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Hi there! It's RaulHC here and I want to introduce you to my brand-new blog :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id="whatisthisabout"&gt;What is this about?&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;'Get comfortable being uncomfortable'&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous quote resumes what this blog is all about. I'm not a person that feels really confortable showing the world some of my thoughts, work or&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/welcome/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">480918fc-b53e-4422-a7a4-ddd5737ed5dd</guid><category>confort-zone</category><category>software-engineering</category><category>personal</category><dc:creator>Raul HC</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 20:52:00 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/11/light-bulb.jpg" medium="image"/><content:encoded>&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/11/light-bulb.jpg" alt="Welcome!"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hi there! It's RaulHC here and I want to introduce you to my brand-new blog :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id="whatisthisabout"&gt;What is this about?&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;'Get comfortable being uncomfortable'&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous quote resumes what this blog is all about. I'm not a person that feels really confortable showing the world some of my thoughts, work or ideas. It's a pet project that I will use to learn some new things getting out of my comfort zone. It's also a personal &lt;em&gt;repository&lt;/em&gt; where I would try to contribute to the internet with some of my knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's a diary about things I have done related to programming mostly. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's a blog where I will write about some things that catch my eye about anything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's a place where express myself and practice some english witting. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's all of the above and more. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you want to take a look and take advantage of anything write here, you are welcome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: This is a gosh blog hosting on Github&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>